司S溥（ 中文台~t生 ）   至\u作
N人     他  生砭  天xA
Mutants...born with extraordinary abilities...
可他依然稚嫩    在黑暗中摸索   で笏的方向
and yet, still, they are children stumbling in the dark...searching for guidance.
天x若不伴有  ゴ蟮男男       就成橐环N {咒
A gift can often be a curse.
就像一凡胎  若碛辛顺岚    他不住自己的心   想w得x太更近   而@等於捉死
Give someone wings,and they may fly too close to the sun.
他有了 A知未淼 能力    他就  害怕  遇到未
Give them the power of prophecy...and they may live in fear of the future.
如果你o了他  最大的天x
Give them the greatest gifts of all...
h超常人的  巨大力量 。 又不克制他的 j望    他就想  裁世界
powers beyond imagination...and they may think they're meant to rule the world.
尼_河谷  公元前3600年
恩・沙巴・奴
En Sabah Nur.
F在 您⒛苡肋hy治@世界了 我的主人
Now you will rule for eternity, my lord.
沉睡吧
Sleep.
_始D移
Let the transference begin.
紊袷芩腊
Death to the false god.
保o好主人
Protect him!
我大家都知道
As everyone knows,
1973年Y束以後
the existence of mutants was first discovered...
在巴黎h上     人第一次lF了N人的存在
during the Paris Peace Accords,after the Vietnam War in 1973.
六天之後     我H眼目睹了 其中一名N人
Six days later, we all watched as one of those mutants...
艾瑞克・mx     在白m前的空地上
Erik Lehnsherr, attacked the President...
u袅    y    和其他乳w
and the Cabinet on the lawn of the White House.
而最K    一位年p的    N人    阻止了他
Their lives were saved by a young mutant who stopped him.
mx    成了  世界  ^通犯      至今去向不明
Now, Lehnsherr escaped and became the world's most-wanted fugitive.
至於她     m然]人^她
And as for her, she disappeared as well.
不^    她已    成榱     新r代的    象徵
But she has become the symbol of a new age...
人    她    改  @世界的    英雄
the face of a world that will never be the same again.
你  χ    我的女孩    眨眼
You winking at my girl?
你的   女孩
Your girl?
你看上去   可以   她爹了
I guess you do look old enough to be her father.
打_一下     晌恍』镒
Excuse me, gentlemen...
你   有什N    要f的
is there something you'd like to share with the rest of the class?
我能   去下    洗手g
Can I please go to the bathroom?
我的    呻b眼睛    感X    很不舒服
I think there's something seriously wrong with my eyes.
好吧     斯科特  ……
Fine, Scott. And afterwards...
你    ^   校Lk公室    向他解一下
why don't you stop by the principal's office and explain to him...
槭颤N    你又在   n堂   vy
that you're disrupting class again?
不用我路吧
I trust you know the way.
-     我JR
- 很好
- Yeah, I do. - Okay.
不     坐下     都等一下
No, hang on! Hang on!
嗨
Hey!
我知道    你中    ^大多档  人
Now, I know most of you were, what?
r   只有   7  q    左右
Around seven years old at that time?
_ 默 斯
Summers!
我知道    你在@
I know you're in here.
你在哭
What, are you crying?
我 ]揍你呢
I haven't even kicked your ass yet.
_默斯 想我女朋友
Summers! You want to eyeball my girl?
|柏林
耶
Yeah!
十霰荣
Ten fights waged.
十鲞B
Ten fights won.
羽翼鹗
The Winged Warrior.
的  猛禽
The Bird of Prey.
死亡天使
The Angel of Death.
他就是天使
ANGEL!
耶
Yeah!
我掌g送大K^
Let's hear it for the fat man!
下一位挑鹫
Our next challenger...
他碜
comes straight...
慕尼黑RF
from the Munich Circus.
女士 先生
Ladies and gentlemen,
唯一 能和天使车
the only one that could take on an Angel...
只有魔鬼
is the Devil himself.
我g迎
I give you...
令人@奇的
the amazing...
怪@G的
the fantastic...
夜行者
NIGHTCRAWLER!
小  心
Caution
高弘
High voltage!
抱歉 N人
Sorry mutants!
嗨
Hey.
你是不是迷路了 小咪
Did you get lost little mouse?
角Y鲈谀沁
The fight is over there.
和我打 否t我都得死
Fight! Or they'll kill us both!
高潮就快砹
And it's about to get exciting.
你是指@
Ah, you mean this?
夜行者
Nightcrawler!
夜行者 夜行者
Nightcrawler! Nightcrawler!
我很抱歉 我很抱歉 我很抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm sorry!
他  往那  跑了
They went that way!
你能
You can...
幻形
transform.
你是那
You're her.
- 英雄 - 我不是
- The hero. - I'm nobody.
什N英雄
I'm not a hero.
快x_@
Let's get out of here.
波m     普什旆
回去睡好X    亨Y克
Have a good night, Henryk.
你也是    米洛什
You too, Milosz.
嗨
Hi, Honey.
Hi.
很累吧
Good day?
F在不累了
Better now.
尼娜  在哪
Where's Nina?
在後院     和朋友在一起
Out back. With her friends.
@首歌是l教你唱的   爸爸
Where did you learn that song, Papa?
是我父母教我的
I learned it from my parents.
他的父母    教了他
And they learned it from their parents.
一直    髁讼
And them from theirs.
有一天
And one day...
你也    唱o    你的孩子  的
you'll sing it to your children, too.
他後碓觞N了     你的父母
What happened to them? Your parents.
在我小的r候
They were taken from me...
他被人ё吡
when I was a little boy.
可他依然
But they're still here.
在我心Y
Inside.
有@Y
And here.
和你在一起
With you.
那有人把你也ё
Is someone going to take you away?
不的
Never.
我     兄弟z的能力      真相似
I guess we're more alike than we thought.
他不我的
He won't listen to us.
他是那N ……
He's just... He's being...
斯科特
Scott.
我
Let me try.
@郝上去好像很f
Smells pretty old in here.
是W校是博物^
Is this a school or a museum?
再走一A
One more.
有最後一A  好了
And last one. There you go.
心交流  【 走路看著c 】
Watch where you're going.
我看不到
I can't.
你    你在和lf
Who are you talking to?
我
Me.
可我才明明到了
I just heard you in my head.
我心`感和x心g
I'm telepathic. I read minds.
x我hc
Well, stay out of mine.
e     M我     X子Y
I don't need some weird girl creeping around in there.
放心 斯科特   ]什N好看的
Don't worry, Scott.There's not much to see.
嗨    等等    我]f^  我叫    斯科特
Hey, wait. I didn't tell you my name.
的_]有
No, you didn't.
v克斯・_默斯
Alex Summers?
h克・考伊
Hank McCoy!
那大子{毛怪去哪毫
Whoa! What happened to the big, blue, furry you?
F在我能控制我自己了
I keep him under control now.
我大哥    斯科特
This is my brother, Scott.
嗨    斯科特
Hey, Scott.
我是h克・考伊 @旱睦
I'm Hank McCoy.I'm one of the teachers here.
教授在哪
Where's the professor?
要想氐赘淖
"To break forth bloodily,
那就   必   我的^去   消失
then the past must be obliterated...
造就   一   全新的_始
"and a new start made.
我念^_始    忘^去的一切
"Let us now start fresh..."without remembrance...
e我迷失在    自己的^去和未碇g
"rather than live forward...and backward at the same time."
好了  大家X得作者  在@段的r候    他想表_的是什N意思
Now, what on earth do we think that the author meant...when he wrote all that?
我把@}做你的回家作I
That's going to be your assignment for tomorrow.
大家回去以後好好 F在可以下n了
Top marks, everyone. Class dismissed.
v克斯
Alex.
- 很高d到你
- 我也是
- It's good to see you. - You too.
好久不    看上去不e
You look well. It's been a while.
是啊    你看著也不e
It has. Not too bad yourself.
xx
Thank you.
@是我哥    斯科特
This is my brother, Scott.
你好    斯科特
Hello, Scott.
g迎淼    天x少年W校
Welcome to the School for the Gifted.
是     我可不X得@是N天x
Yeah. It doesn't exactly feel like a gift.
每人一_始都@NX得
It never does, at first.
一人  控制自己能力的第一步
The first step in understanding one's power...
就是  t解自己的能力
is learning the extent of it.
只有@   才是如何控制  的  良性_始
Only then can...we begin the process of teaching you how to control it.
才能你W如何去控制它
we begin the process of teaching you how to control it.
如果你意留下淼脑 我可以保C
If you do decide to stay,I can promise you...
等你倪@鹤叱鋈r
that by the time you're done here,
你就能蚧w你原淼纳活
you'll be able to go back into the world...
甚至更好地c常人社硗
and play a stable and productive part in it.
不如你摘下
Why don't you take your bandages off...
我看看是什N情r
and we can have a look at what we're dealing with here?
v克斯     扶他一把
Alex, would you line him up?
他朝著    安全的方向
Face him in the right direction, as it were.
目司驮    河的γ
There's a target just across the water.
_眼睛     著瞄仕
When you open your eyes, try and hit that.
你可以_眼睛了
You can open your eyes, Scott.
]什N好怕的 很安全
There's nothing to be afraid of.It's quite...
小心   退後
Look out! Get back!
退後   退後
Get back! Get back!
那棵   是我祖父   五qrN下的
My grandfather planted that tree when he was five years old.
我常常    在那棵渖    Fa
I used to swing... from the branches of it, myself.
我想   那是我的    最
I think that was probably my favorite tree.
所以    我不能留下了
Does that mean I'm expelled?
恰恰  相反
On the contrary.
你被  取了
You're enrolled.
埃及   __
你@嘿u地毯
Do you sell rugs?
你不能S便到@
You're not allowed in this area.
@l地毯u
This rug is for sale?
我都f了
I said, this...
地震了
Earthquake!
快回去睡X 孩子
Back to bed, please, my darling.Back to bed.
她又做噩袅
She's doing it again.
快回到床上去 幼骺禳c
Back to bed, please, everyone.
芪 回去好
Jesse, back to bed, please.
快回到   自己床上去
Come on now. Spit-spot, back to bed.
P莉 ・ 安娜     快回到床上
Carrie Anne, come on now. Back to bed.
]^她@
Never seen it like this.
我也是
Nor I.
e其他孩子到@
Don't let any of the children come this way.
琴
Jean.
Jean!
琴
我想 我看到世界末日了
I saw the end of the world.
我能
I could feel...
感受到到都是死亡
all this death.
那只是
It was just a dream.
太真了
No, it felt real.
我知道
I know.
你的意念是我所^最大的
Your mind is the most powerful I've ever seen.
的意念  是一  生命w
It can convince itself...
不 @次不一
No, no...
不是蔚淖x心g 或者是心`感
It's not just the mind-reading or the telekinesis...
@次不一
it's something else.
有巨大 黑暗的力量 在崛起
Some dark power inside and it's growing.
像 野火 一
Like a fire.
我以槲铱刂频迷碓胶昧
I thought I was getting better.
是
You are.
你是越碓胶
You will.
只要得耐心c
You just have to be patient.
不  不   你]法w
No, no. You don't know...
那N    害怕]眼的    恐
what it's like to be afraid to shut your eyes.
被自己的   另一意R   吞掉
To be trapped inside your own head.
不   我想我能w
Oh, I think I do.
我也曾被   X中的那些音   折磨
It wasn't so long ago that I was plagued by voices, myself.
凡人受的苦
All their suffering.  All their pain.
藏匿的秘密
Their secrets.
我怕   有一天   我去  害了e人
I'm afraid one day I'm going to hurt someone.
躺下吧
Lie back.
每人   都害怕    未能理解 的事
Everyone fears that which they do not understand.
有一天   你可以W控制自己
You will learn to control your powers.
你Wr
And when you do...
你就不再怕了
you'll have nothing to fear.
@次的噩  和  以前不同
Her nightmares were different this time.
或S  @印C了  在室l生的怪事
It could account for something I saw when I was in my lab earlier.
\   地震    一股能量浪涌
There was some kind of tremor.Like an energy surge.
我的   探yx   了
I picked it up on one of my meters.
你是f   琴造成的  ？
You're saying Jean created it?
不   是e的|西
No. I'm saying something else did.
可能  琴只是感到了
Maybe she was reacting to it.I don't know.
但   震中   是在地球的   另一端
But the epicenter was halfway around the world.
另一端  ？ ！
Halfway around the world?
所以  我希望你  也看一看
That's why I was hoping you could take a look.
看看能找到什N
Let's see what we can find.
g迎您 教授
Welcome, Professor.
能量源  @示  在 __
Okay, the source came from Cairo.
我把坐 {好
I'll put in the coordinates.
我得 x_@Y
I gotta get out of here.
蟾嫔霞
Give them a report.
看什N了
What? What is it?
我得告V他   @事菏钦娴
Something happened here.I can tell them it's real.
是她
It's her.
l
Who?
- 莫伊拉 - 什N
- Moira. - What?
莫伊拉 ・ 格泰戈特
Moira MacTaggert?
fc
Give me the details.
她 很美  ]什Nq月痕E
She looks amazing.She's barely aged a day.
不  我是f
No. I meant...
她跑那  去致
What is she doing there?
中情局和@事 有什NPS
What does the CIA want with this?
她正想回 m利 蟾孢@事
She's going back to Langley to deliver a report.
我得去 m利 一趟
I'm going to go there...
看看她 能不能 臀
see if she knows something about the tremor.
便能看看她
And you want to go see Moira.
我是得去看看她   我是f
I want to go check her out. Check out...
看看 情r
the situation.
莫伊拉 ・ 格泰戈特
Moira MacTaggert.
去 老相R
It's like a ghost from the past.
你]有做e 你救了那人
You did a good thing. You saved that man.
@不是重c
That's not the point.
重c是  我暴露了    你也  跟著倒霉
If I'm exposed, we're all exposed.
必搬家
We have to go.
@是我的家
This is our home.
有女
This is our daughter's home.
有我才算家
We are her home.
遇你那晚 我就告V了你 我是l
I told you who I was,the first night I met you.
因槲倚湃文
I trusted you then.
F在我要你也信任我
I need you to trust me now.
我^不能留在@
We can't stay here anymore.
我去叫尼娜
I'll get Nina.
Sweetheart.
她不在房g
She's not in her room.
後院也]看到人
And I don't see her out back.
尼 娜 ……
Nina ……
尼 娜
Nina
你]事吧
Are you alright?
她]事
She's fine.
那就 放了她啊
Then let her go!
我的
We will.
我只是想 和你
We just wanted to have a word
你]有  警徽
You're not wearing your badges.
不 金
No metal.
今天工S  有人R  看到了一些事
Some guys at the factory said they saw something today.
不合常理 的事
Something that didn't add up.
把  你的弓箭  放下
Put your weapons away.
你是好市民   亨Y克
You've been a good citizen, Henryk...
一好居 好工人
A good neighbor... a good worker.
我意相信你的 人品
I want to believe that's who you are.
他是好人
It is.
但上]人真正t解你
But nobody in this town really knows you.
不  你知道我的
Yes you do.
我是亨Y克 ・ 古斯基
I am Henryk Gurzsky.
雅各布  我去你家吃^晚餐
Jakob, I've had dinner in your home...
你一直 m著我
And you were lying the whole time.
是我引狼入室
I brought a killer into my house.
@是你
Is this you?
你就是  蠹上f的  f磁王
Are you the one they call Magneto?
我跟你走
Take me in.
你
Please...
放了我的  妻
Just let my daughter go.
到你那喝
Go with your mother.
爸爸
Please...
你e走
Don't leave me.
爸爸  e走
I'm not going to let them take you.
尼娜
Nina.
怎N回事
What's going on?
小孩   也有   特功能
She's one of them?
快她停下
Tell her to stop!
她控制不了
She can't control it!
你著她了
She's scared of you!
我  不他   你走
I'm not going to let them take you!
快她停下
Make her stop!
尼娜   尼娜
Nina! Nina!
尼娜
Nina.
尼娜  尼娜  尼娜   不
Nina, Nina, no...
不   不行   不行
No, please. Please!
你就是bi
不行
Please.
槭颤N ё  我的孩子
Not my babies.
槭颤N  @N  ξ
Is this what you want from me?
槭颤N  @N恨我
Is this what I am?
你知道小偷的下鍪鞘颤N
You know what we do to thieves.
x一b手吧
Pick a hand.
蛄
Enough.
如果你是一夥的  你最好 L
If you're with her, I suggest you walk away.
懂]
While you still can.
L
Walk away
l在管制  @世界
Who rules this world?
你f的是 哪
What language is that?
小丑  你是 混哪的
Clown-face. What's the deal?
快 L
Beat it!
我怕了
I'm sorry.
感受 到了
You can't feel it, can you?
F在感受到了吧
Now you feel it.
中央 情缶
所以@啄 你都] 看^她
So you really haven't seen her in all these years?
也]找^她  ]用C房的主X 看看她 ？
You never looked her up? Not even in Cerebro?
v克斯 你把我偷Q狂
Alex! What do you take me for,some kind of pervert?
是  我是偷看^一次   好吧  纱
Yes, I looked her up once. Twice.
但我很久都]再看了   好
But not in a long time, all right?
你怎N放下的  你 蔚昧
How did you leave things? Any hard feelings?
]k法    可人得活下去
Not likely. Everybody take a break.
我抹去了她P於我的所有
I wiped her mind of all memories of us.
海  古巴  那次事件的所有
The beach, Cuba... that whole time.
那是很久以前的事了
It was so long ago, Alex.
那r人  不知道  有N人  的存在
Before the world knew about mutants.
我X得那  λ最好
I felt it was the best thing for her.
那你呢
And for you?
我不重要
Didn't really matter what was best for me.
莫伊拉
Moira...
格泰戈特   你好
MacTaggert, hello!
允S我自我介B一下
Allow me to introduce myself.
- 我是 ……
- 查斯 ・ 艾克斯S
- I'm Professor... - Charles Xavier.
我然知道你是l
I know exactly who you are.
你知道
You do?
然
Of course I do.
你的文我全都x^
I have read all of your papers.
很高d K於到你本人了
It's a pleasure to finally meet you.
莫伊拉 ・ 格泰戈特
Moira MacTaggert.
- v克斯 ・ _默斯
- 快坐
- Alex Summers. - Have a seat.
把它 扔地上 就好
Just throw that on the floor.
能再到你真是太好了
It's wonderful to see you again.
我是f再次  初次
To meet you again, for the first time.
你有鹤
You've got a son?
是的
Yes.
那他有丈夫 是
Does he have a husband?
你有  丈夫
Do you have a husband?
前 夫
I had a husband...
不^   我 @行
but it's hard to do this job...
不可能   每天都   按r   回家做
and make it home in time for dinner.
f得太α
Good, good.
奚在所y免  Π
We all make choices, right?
是的   我懂
Yes, we do.
- 教授
- 什 N ？
Professor. Yes?
好的
Yes.
我 希望你能  告V我  昨天在埃及  l生了什N
I was, we were hoping that you would...tell us about what happened yesterday in Egypt.
抱歉  @都是C密
I'm afraid that's classified information.
o意冒犯
I don't mean to be rude...
但  你是怎N  M淼
but how did you get in here?
我有   5 嘞
I have level-five clearance.
自73年  人lF了  N人
Ever since the world found out about mutants in '73...
S之就   出F了   S多  狂岱肿
there have been cults...
他把N人的出F
who see them as some kind of...
作   上帝再F   徵兆
Second Coming or sign of God.
我在追查其中一信徒
I was tracking one of them.
他自Q   阿希・恩・沙巴・奴
They call themselves Ashir En Sabah Nur...
名字取自一古人
named after an ancient being...
他相信  他就是始祖
they believe to be the world's first.
什N  始祖
The world's first what?
N人的   始祖
The world's first mutant.
我以   N人是   @世o的事
I thought mutants didn't evolve until this century.
@是我的理   可是@些人相信
That's the common theory, yes,but these guys believe...
兹f年前   N人始祖   就已出生
that the first mutant was born tens of thousands of years ago.
K且他相信   他再次起
And they believe he will rise again.
他找遍  世上所有的古E
They've been searching ancient sites all around the world for clues.
以で笏的E
These hieroglyphs...
象形文字  d了  @N超能
describe a specific set of powers...
凡人]有的  力量
greater than any man could possess.
他相信他能活到F在
They think he lived all that time?
他也是模模糊糊    但   他就相信他有能力
Yes and no.They believe he had the ability...
把自己的主意R   D移到e人身上
to transfer his consciousness from body to body.
每他快死r
And whenever he was close to death...
就Q一新的身w
he would just take on a new body.
而@些身w中   有些是N人
Some of these may have been the bodies of mutants...
@   他就能  吸取  各家所L
enabling him to take their powers...
e累多N的天x
amassing various abilities over the years.
-  一  全能的  N人
-  正 解
An all-powerful mutant.  Exactly.
而o他  出F在哪     他的身  跟著  四N人
And wherever this being was    he always had four principle followers.
他的T徒
Disciples.
他x予他力量    肀Ｗo自己
Protectors he would imbue with powers.
就像}Y的
Like the Four Horsemen...
天⑺尿T士
of the Apocalypse.
他在抄u模仿 《 }  》
He got that one from the Bible.
或者 } 在抄u他
Or the Bible got it from him.
而且 o他到哪
And wherever he ruled...
都以  碾y  Y束
eventually, it would end in disaster.
也S他就是《}》中v的   浩 劫 ……
Cataclysm. Some kind of...
…… 天
Apocalypse
世界末日
The end of the world.
【 不得不f   阿波_ 】
I must say, Apollo...
【 你扮成人  的幼  太英俊了 】
the way you ape human behavior is remarkable.
【 我可是阿波_ 】
I am Apollo.
@上居然有第 2 N人
I've never seen another mutant in this town.
你f埃及Z
You speak Egyptian?
阿拉伯Z呢
Arabic?
英Z
English?
【 我是科W家 】
I'm a scientist.
【 我研究的主要I 】
My particular specialty...
勇敢的  鹗
Great fighter.
她是我的英雄
She's my hero.
我要得像她一
I want to be like her.
@河行┏缘   但不多
There's some food here. Not much.
【 我不相信  】
I don't believe it.
【 你是畚业 】
You love me.
【 勰    ef傻了 】
Love you? Illogical.
【  我不是  p易仰慕精英的  牧羊女 】I'm not some simple shepherdess you can awe.
【 c其勰   不如   凵弦环N   菌 】
Why, I could no more love you...than I could love a new species of bacteria.
你在致
What are you doing?
W
Learning.
【 街上到都是   反  K攻打阿富汗 的    [行伍】
In the streets, there is outrage against the Soviet invasion of Afghanistan......in a brotherhood of our kind.
【   N人   FY 】
Several demonstrations.
【 其中一鲩兵     在波士De行 】
One of them was held in Boston,and Bruce Morton has the story.
【 自  核武器  l明以後     美不再l 】
Since the advent of nuclear weapons,the United States does not start fights.
武器
Weapons.
【 人]有^     如此大的力量 】
Never before has man possessed so much power.
【 美 K   成了  超大 】
Soviet Union and United States being superpowers...
超  大
Superpowers.
弱小的人
The weak...
管制著地球
have taken the earth.
榱诉@些   他背叛了我
For this, I was betrayed.
那些  紊  闻枷
False gods. Idols.
⒉痛嬖
No more.
我回砹
I have returned.
【 湫碌拿魈臁
A new tomorrow...
【 慕裉扉_始 】
that starts today.
你是哪淼
Where did you come from?
娜祟  迷失方向  之前的r代
A time before man lost his way.
g迎淼  8 0 年代
Welcome to the '80s.
地球  需要 ……
This world needs to be...
Q 化
Cleansed.
什N
What?
拯救
Saved.
你@y⑷   救不了地球的
You can't save the world just going around killing people.
有法律w系   不允S人  S便⑷
There's laws, systems in place for that kind of thing.
我的孩子
My child...
槭颤N要束`自己的天x
why do you enslave yourself?
你致锬
What are you doing?
你得更大
Making you stronger.
女 神
My goddess.
是的
Yes.
【 你是Φ 】
You were right.
【 那r代已^去了 】
The time is past.
【 @  不再信神了 】
There is no room for gods.
我槭颤N  不能跟著你
Why can't I go with you?
我喜g  胃
I told you, I work alone.
等在@
Wait there.
看到你的  我很高d
Always good to see your face.
即使那不是你的
Even if it's not yours.
我要 一份  通行C
Papers and passage for one.
好的    @位先生想去哪
Where's the gentleman going, if I may ask?
你S便吧   我不管
Don't know, don't care.
我只救人   e的不P心
I just save his life.What he does with it is up to him.
l虮   魔形女
Mystique, the mercenary.
e@N叫我
Don't call me that.
不你  把自己  假b成  什N人
No matter how much you pretend to be someone else...
卡利班都能J出你
Caliban knows who you are.
我能   感到    N人的  一切信息
If there's anything worth knowing about mutants...
@是  卡利班  N能力
Caliban knows it.
魔形女
Mystique.
再@N咄咄逼人   知道你  什N下
Why don't you ask your psychics what'll happen to you if you keep pushing me?
什N  下
What'll happen?
`蝶有c吃醋了
Psylocke gets a little jealous.
但  卡利班  就是  δ  有好感
But Caliban likes you.
卡利班喜gX
Caliban likes money.
卡利班  δ  是有好感
Caliban likes you so much...
喜g到   免Mo你    一l信息
he wants to give you free information...
P於你的老朋友
about an old friend...
以前是  朋友
from back when you had friends.
你得
Do you remember...
艾瑞克 ・ mx
Erik Lehnsherr?
通`  感到  他在波m
My girls got a flash of him in Poland.
他 留下了 好企w
He left quite a few dead bodies in his wake...
包括  他老婆  和  孩子
including his wife and daughter.
新    很快就播   不^呢
Should be in the news soon enough
卡利班  想先告V你
but Caliban gives you a little head start.
你能有多快
How fast are you?
多快
How fast?
能鬏到多h
How far can you cover?
^的地方    去^的地方   就行
As far as I can see or if I've been there before.
- 走     爪 行 者
- 是                 夜 行 者 ……
Come with me, Crawler.Actually, it's Nightcrawler.
而我的本名是 ……
And my real name is...
特 ・ 瓦格{
Kurt Wagner.
R片是用  t石英  做成的
The lenses are made of some ruby quartz I had lying around.
能  折射  激光
They should be able to refract your optic beams...
然後  保存在矢量鲅Y
and keep them contained within their own vector fields.
Try them on.
好了
Okay.
_ 吧
Go ahead.
等等   @不行
Wait, sorry, no.
好了
Okay.
- 好了 - 好了 戆
- Now? - Yeah, you're good.
好的
All right.
我看了
I can see.
xx
Thank you.
教授 xx你 你太害了
Professor, thank you. You're a genius.
不 我
No.
我不是教授   那是我的目
I'm not a professor. I wish...
那是l
Who's that?
琴 ・ 葛蕾   你z^
I believe you two met. That's Jean Grey.
r  你撞^她
You bumped into her when you arrived.
- 等等 是她
-
- Wait, that's her? - Yeah.
嗨
Hey.
你能看了
You can see.
@罕任蚁胂裰械暮
Yeah. It's not as bad as I thought here.
怪 物
Freak.
- 提醒下那新淼
-
- Someone should warn the new kid. - Yeah. Someone should tell him.
他是怕我
They're still scared of me.
嗨 我F在有特u的眼R了
Hey, I have special glasses now.
他怕的不是你   是我
They're not scared of you. They're scared of me.
你不是唯一 一  尚未  掌控能力 的人
You're not the only one who can't fully control your powers.
那Nf
Wait, so...
昨晚 房子u晃
last night, when the house shook...
是你值
that was you?
你失望了   你不是W校Y  最人的
Sorry to break it to you, but you're not the biggest freak in the school.
@倒^一次
Well, that's a first.
瑞  雯
Raven.
我    ……
I... You're...
不是{色的
Not blue?
看砦有共同c了
Looks like you and I have that in common, now.
不   不   我意思是 ……
No, no, I meant...
回砹
you're back.
]想到你回
Never thought I'd see you here again.
我也]想到
Yeah, me neither.
我是{色的
I'm blue.
我是特
I'm Kurt.
哦
Oh, right.
特 ・ 瓦格{
Kurt Wagner.
g迎
Welcome.
打烊了
We're closed.
我就f怎N冷``的
I knew I felt a chill in the air.
你怎NM淼
How did you get in here?
就@NM淼    我在找N人
We let ourselves in. We are looking for mutants.
你有  找N人的  特功能       所以  我砹
Since you know where to find them,we came here.
卡利班不JR你
Caliban doesn't know you.
我在找最的N人
We're looking for the strongest.
有 事
Everything all right?
] 事
I'm fine, Psylocke.
你уX了
How much money do you have?
]有
None.
卡利班f^了
Like Caliban said...
我打烊了 懂
we are closed. Yeah?
我需要 椭   我的孩子
I need your help, my child.
你L得  不像我爹
You don't look like Caliban's father.
除了 d  有c像我爹
Maybe a little bit up here.
你都是我的孩子
You are all my children...
而你迷失了   因楦e了I路人
and you're lost, because you follow blind leaders.
那些愚蠢的紊
These false gods...
弱者 制定的  制度
systems of the weak.
我  不允S  他  ^承我的 ……
They've ruined my world...
地 球
No more.
你想要什N
What do you want?
我要你
I want you...
去感受  你能力的  O限
to feel the full reach of your power.
只l]了  真能力的  冰山一角
You've only had a taste of your true strength.
我不像  其他人
Unlike others...
他  希望  控制
who seek to control you...
我  希望  放
I want to set you free.
我知道  你要找的  那N人  在哪
I know the kind of mutants you're looking for.
我能 你去
And I know where to find them.
@是我第一次砻
It's my first time in America.
我很d^  能⒂^  你的文化
I'm very excited to see your culture.
在@  你⒂^不到
Well, you're not gonna see it here.
@只有  英z留  在美的 文化
The only thing American about this place is that it used to be British.
@位是  斯科特
This is Scott.
跟你一   新淼
He's new here, too.
越z  已  好了
And I'm already up for a prison break.
一起 逛逛   去不
What do we say, we take this blue guy on a little field trip?
附近  有  大摩
I'm sure there's a mall around here, somewhere.
摩  是什N
What's a mall?
你我
他去 R一下  大型物中心
All right, now this is a matter of national pride. Civic duty.
斯科特
Scott.
咋了  你也被  P在@  好久了
What? You've been cooped up here for a long time...
教授 又  不在家
and the Professor's not even home.
我想去  大型物中心  __眼界
I'd like to go to the mall.
越 z
Try it.
很好
All right.
教授的在哪
Where does he keep his cars?
到了]有   L
Or should I say "piss off"?
就是@人
This is the guy?
曾是
He used to be.
我不知道  他的翅膀
I didn't know his wings were...
我走吧
Let's get out of here.
他已  不比那傲
His fighting days are done.
不  他行
No, they're not.
你 是 l
What the hell is this?
我o你  一好|西
I want to give you something.
我要的   你o不了
There's nothing you can give me that I want.
不     他 能 o
Yes, there is.
很好    孩 子
Yes, my son.
]e
Yes.
站起    我的天使
Rise, my angel.
w 吧
Rise.
超音速    防爆b置    [身功能
Hypersonic, blast resistant,stealth technology.
@  人
That's impressive.
它  哪  w出去
How are you ever gonna get it out of here?
不用 心
Well, that's okay.
@球  有 可移邮  屋
I built a retractable roof into the basketball court.
你 在@  造了  一架  痿YC
Hank, you're building a warplane down here.
A盛D事件之後
After what happened in Washington,
重  X鹁 了
I thought we were going to come back and start the X-Men,
就像我  以前想的
like we all used to talk about.
但
But...
查斯  要的是W生   不是士兵
Charles wants students, not soldiers.
他相信 人性善    另一面不防
And he thinks the best of people. He has hope.
那你呢
And you?
我相信  人性善
You know, I think we should hope for the best.
同r   人性  有善  必有
And prepare for the worst.
相生 相w
I think the world needs the X-Men.
F在  你回砹     咱  一起  袼
And maybe now that you're back,  you could help me convince him. We could start it together.
我  是榱  艾瑞克  的事
Hank, I'm here about Erik.
好吧   艾瑞克
Right. Erik.
然
Yeah. Of course.
然 了
Of course.
他  遇到  麻┝
I think he might be in some kind of trouble.
大 ！ 麻 ！  ！
Real trouble.
他  哪次  不是  大麻
Isn't he always?
你  有人  把昨天的事 ……
Some of you spoke to the police...
告V了 警察
about what you believe you witnessed here yesterday.
你  想知道  我的能力
You want to know my powers...
我 是 l
know who I am...
想看看  我要致
see what I can do?
我 F在  你看
I'll show you.
想像一下   你生命Y   最鄣娜
Think of the person you love most in your life.
妻 子
Your wife.
母 H
Mother.
孩 子
Daughter.
想LL  @  感X
Now that person will know what it is to lose someone they love.
和痛苦  作伴
And live with that pain.
一  子
Forever.
亨Y克 求你了
Henryk, please.
e@N做
Don't do this.
我不叫  亨Y克
My name isn't Henryk.
我叫做   f磁王
My name is Magneto.
你 l 啊
Who the fuck are you?
e^
Stay back.
不管你是l     今天 我要  ⒘ 他
Whoever you are...don't try to stop me from killing these men.
我 不是  砭  他的
I'm not here for them.
我榱四
I'm here for you.
^ 看看吧
Come and see.
W 斯 S 辛
@是  你能力  Q生之地
This is where your power was born.
也是你  同胞  被⒅地
And this is where your people were slaughtered.
你不我磉@
You shouldn't have brought me here.
什 N
Why?
你很害怕磉@
Are you afraid to be here?
你 避不_ 的   艾瑞克
You can't escape it, Erik.
你 是 l
Who are you?
埃洛希姆     神M      太神
（  分e是   希伯   中    埃及   ι竦慕蟹   ）
Elohim, Shen, Ra.
o递中   我有太多Q^
I've been called many names over many lifetimes.
我  Q生於  死亡
I am born of death.
我  肩  c燃  人的缰火
I was there to spark...and fan the flame of man's awakening.
推  外星  文明巨的  前M
To spin the wheel of civilization.
把人的文明  B根拔起
And when the forest would grow rank...
播撒  外星的  N子
and needed clearing for new growth...
我⒓缲使命   c燃@把火
I was there to set it ablaze.
我爸  被屠   你在哪Y
Where were you... when my father and mother were slaughtered in this place?
沉 睡
Asleep.
困在  黑暗 中
Trap  ped in darkness.
我r   不在你身        但F在 我回w了
I was not there for you, my son.  But I am here now.
只有我知道  你有多
You don't know your own strength,but I do.
用心感受
Reach down.
N藏在  地下
Feel the metal...
金
in the ground.
感受  那份  暗黑
Reach as deep as you can.
你lF   你 的能力
You'll find you have the power...
足以  覆  地球
to move the very Earth itself.
人  建造的  世界  ⒈  氐
Everything they've built will fall!
在那片  U墟 上
And from the ashes of their world...
我   重建   外星文明
we'll build a better one!
昨天  波m中部    一上
Lehnsherr was identified yesterday,
lF了  f磁王  的E
in this small town in central Poland.
波m  I人  呼n  市民  保持定
Leaders from all communities are urging their citizens to remain calm.
警方      烂 搜查
As police and armed forces are mobilizing to find Lehnsherr...
⒆柚顾  l起  再一次攻
...before he can strike again.
任何人  有索
If anyone has information about Lehnsherr...
毡   M  警方      K且注意  小心行事
contact your local authorities immediately...and proceed with caution...
他可是  一  O危U的  人
as he is considered extremely...
- 彼得
- 怎N了
Peter.What's up?
- 看你致锬
- ]事   忙著呢
- Just checking on you.   - I'm good. Playing Pac-Man.
- 你_定  ]看  @
【 在人 c祝  人 c N人  和平相  10L年r   有一@人的消息 】
- You sure you weren't watching this? - This news comes at a time   between mutants and mankind.
你是不是想去找他
You're going after him, aren't you?
你不是 我 多出去 走走
You wanted me to get out of the house more, right?
我r不住你
I can't stop you. Nobody can.
相信我   和他一起  ]好事
But trust me, this won't end well.
少和他胶
Nothing does with him.
我 不怕 他
I'm not afraid of him.
那是     你   不t解   他
You should be.
【 删S  天x少年  W校 】
查斯 ・  删S      教授
我 看^  描@地方  的
I've read so much about this place.
槭颤N  我有N  ……
But being here,it actually seems kind of...
熟 悉 感
familiar.
真 妙
Strange.
是 嘛  ……   下吧
Quite.  Shall we?
【  映 】
星球大 3     ^地w
要我f   是 《 帝反  》  最好
I'm just saying, Empire is still the best.
∏檠}s    人物SM
It's the most complex,the most sophisticated...
而且  不怕  悲K  Y尾
wasn't afraid to have a dark ending.
是  但  如果  ]有  第 1 集
Yeah, but come on.If it wasn't for the first one...
你也  看不著  後的  准
you wouldn't have any of the rest of the movies.
至少我  都同     第 3 集  最差
Well, at least we can all agree,
h克   你在
Hank. Are you in here?
我想你  硪
I'd like you to meet...
莫伊拉
Moira.
瑞雯
Raven.
抱歉   咱JR
I'm sorry, have we met?
@是h克      她是  格泰戈特  探T
Hank, Alex, Agent MacTaggert,
我 能和  瑞雯      为  Z删
would you give us just one moment, please?
O K
Of course.
她樯恫徽JR我      她^我
Charles, why didn't she recognize me? She knew me in this form.
年在古巴    你x_以後
Well, after you left me on the beach in Cuba...
我  清除了  她的      坐
I took her memories of that time. Have a seat.
真w慕她
Lucky girl.
看你 真好      瑞雯
It's good to see you, Raven.
回家 了
Welcome home.
@ 不是  我家
This isn't my home.
至少  以前是
It was once.
不   @是你家     我以前在@  寄居
No, it was your home. I just lived here.
F在  @Y  恿
And I barely even recognize it now.
我  b修  了
You know, I have plans for this place.
我想  把@  b修成  W校
I mean to turn it into a real campus.
一所大W
A university.
不只N人      普通人  也可以
Not just for mutants, either,for humans too.
一起生活
Living and working...
一起成L
growing together.
我以前也相信@些
You know, I really believed that once.
A盛D 事件後     我相信  能改   人的想法
I really believed we could change them after DC.
不是
We did.
不     他依然  害怕 、 恨 我
No, Charles. They still hate and fear us.
他只是   W了   Y貌   掩  而已
It's just harder to see because they're more polite about it.
我倦了  @N
I got sick of living that lie.
所以  @些年  你就  [居了
That's why you're not in your natural blue form.
他  心中的英雄      根本就  不是  那N回事
I'm not gonna be the face of a world that doesn't exist.
我的努力  世界  得更好
Things are better. The world is better.
在你W校Y   可能是
Maybe in Westchester.
在W校外面      N人  仍然在  逃亡
Out there, mutants are still running...
躲藏   提心吊
hiding, living in fear.
]   不等於世界大同
Just because there's not a war,doesn't mean there's peace.
你   告V孩子  真相
You want to teach your kids something,teach them that.
教他   防l   痿Y
Teach them to fight.
不然   他 只能  一子    躲在@
Otherwise they might as well live in this house for the rest of their lives.
你f的  @些^c     和年的   艾瑞克   一模 一
You still sound just like him.
我回    也是因樗
That's why I'm here. He's resurfaced.
他的妻子和孩子     被  了
He had a wife and a child. They were killed.
所以  他⒘   警察
Along with a handful of policemen.
全世界都通他的
The whole world will be looking for him.
所以  得s快  找到他
But you can help me find him before they do.
莫伊拉   希望你  e把@Y的事   f出去
Moira, I'm going to have to ask you to keep this a secret.
我甚至  都不知道  @是啥
I don't even know what this is.
@是主X
It's Cerebro.
升  版
The new model.
]e   室鹊念色  取自 ……
I based the color on...
] 什 N
It doesn't matter.
那些是什N
What are those?
是地球上的  人
Those are all the humans of the world.
而@些
And these...
是 N人
are all the mutants.
我能  感到  他的 思想
I'm connected to all of their minds.
中情局  做  都想  要@C器
The CIA would kill for this.
我知道
I know they would.
你在哪   艾瑞克
Where are you, Erik?
查斯
Charles?
你好   老朋友
Hello, old friend.
我很抱歉    我真的抱歉
I'm sorry. I am so sorry!
我感受到了
I feel your pain.
你的视H之痛
And your loss.
你X得   你能  M我的X子       就懂我的痛了
You think because you can see into my head...you know how it feels?
你礤e地方了   查斯
You're looking in the wrong place,Charles.
不什N    他不  @Nδ
What happened to them,it was terribly wrong.
回戆 艾瑞克    我湍
But come back to us. I can help you.
你 臀
Help me?
想想你的妻    如果她在  ……
Think of your wife,think of your daughter.  What would they have wanted?
她  想要  活命
They would have wanted to live.
我了你的    查斯
I tried your way, Charles.
著  像人  一
I tried to be like them.
蔚  生活著
Live like them.
可  每次  Y局  都一
But it always ends the same way.
他  走  我的一切
They took everything away from me.
F 在
Now...
我要  以暴制暴
we'll take everything from them.
h克
Hank...
他不是一人
he's not alone.
太奇妙了
Extraordinary.
你看到了什N
What do you see?
答 案
The answer.
查斯 等等
Hey, Charles, wait.
我的天
Oh, my God.
xx你我M
Thank you for letting me in.
查斯   快撤出
Charles... Charles, get out! Charles！
@N  大的  力量
I've never felt power like this before.
查斯    快 出
Charles... Charles, get out of there.
怎N回事
What's going on? What's happening?
我 想 ……
I think...
有人  入侵了  主X
Someone's taken over Cerebro.
- 控制了主X
- 榱耸颤N ？
- They've taken control of it. - To do what?
B接查斯
To connect.
人是@
Always the same.
F在   他有了       就不再用石^了
And now, all this.  No more stones.
不再需要L矛     不再需要投石器
No more spears.  No more slings.
不再需要刀    不再需要任何武器
No more swords.
F在我砹     武器   制度   全U
No more weapons!  No more systems!
yy  消失
No more!
不需要   超大
No more superpowers.
查斯
Charles!
h克
Hank!
怎N回事
What the hell is going on?
l  D拥  匙
Who's turning the keys?
咱的人
The men are.
l下的令
Who green-lit the launch?
h克   想想k法
Hank, do something!
P 不 掉
It won't shut down!
c  三叉戟   和   北O星   失了
We've lost contact with all Trident and Polaris subs.
空 @    也是一
The Air Force is reporting the same thing.
他  依  武器
So much faith in their tools...
F代科技  工具
and their  machines.
俄   中
Russia, China...
英    以色列    印度
England, Israel, India.
都l射了核
Everybody's got nukes in the air.
目 是  哪
What's the target? Where are they going?
天上   街毕蛏
Up, straight up.
v克斯
Alex...
-  什N
-  Я怂
- What? - Destroy it!
Я 一切    Я酥髂X
Destroy everything. Destroy Cerebro!
用  n舨
Wreak havoc!
你    爬上了    通天塔
You can fire your arrows...
挑  你的上帝
from the Tower of Babel...
但是   你   永h]有    偎
but you can never...strike... God ...
查斯   醒醒
Charles, are you okay?
艾瑞克
Erik.
查斯
Charles!
v克斯
Alex!
嗨   混蛋
Hey! Hey, asshole!
一切即⒔ 我的孩子
All will be revealed, my child.
停下
Stop!
不
No!
你是  ……
Where did you...
我找教授   我以樗住 @
I was looking for the Professor.I thought he lived here.
他被ё吡
They took him.
快看   就是她
She's the one. It's her.
N人的  英雄
Are you sure?
她是  臀  的
Is she gonna help us?
他崇拜你
They look up to you.
他
Right now...
需要你
they need you.
他需要的不是我
That's not what they need.
太  了
That's awesome!
怎N回事
What happened?
我弟弟  呢
Where's Alex?
看他]
Where's my brother?
我已救出所有人了
Pretty sure I got everybody.
v克斯  x爆c  太近了
Alex was closest to the blast.
v克斯
Alex...
有一公里
We're one click out.
好了 兄弟 浜
All right, boys. This is it.
斯科特
Scott.
t R上就到
Medical assistance is on the way.
保持定
Please remain calm.
t R上就到
Medical assistance is on the way.
保持定
Please remain calm.
t R上就到
Medical assistance is on the way.
保持定
Please remain calm.
t R上就到
Medical assistance is on the way.
嗨   莫伊拉 ・ 格泰戈特    中情局的
Hey! Moira MacTaggert! CIA!
x天x地   你砹
Thank God you're here!
他是  史崔克
Wait!
射
Fire!
把她ё
I want her.
他
Him.
有她
And her.
是 L官
Yes, sir.
不用管孩子
Leave the kids.
- 我怎Nk
- e出
- What do we do? - Keep quiet.
X7    我 最後一次  清查
X-Ray 7, I'm doing a final sweep of the ground.
把人  搬上  wC
Let's get them on the bird!
安 全
Clear!
多你   琴        咱得救人啊
Thanks, Jean. We gotta help them.
特   能我上去
Kurt, can you get us in that thing?
你要上wC ？        被看了  怎Nk
You want to get in there?  What if the soldiers see us?
有我在     他看不到
Don't worry, they won't see us. Trust me.
抓o了
Hold on.
特   把他С鋈
Kurt, get us all out of here!
我   我不`了
I can't!
他PT  以後
When they closed the doors,
出F了  一股   磁
there's some kind of electrical field.
就像  年  我在柏林
It's like Berlin all over.
琴   控制住w行T    不他起w
Jean, get in the pilots' heads. Don't let them take off.
不行   我M不去  他的思S       其他人的也不行
I can't. I can't reach the pilots.  I can't reach anyone.
碜  W洲   洲  的消息        不只美    全世界  核武器  都 失控了
We're also getting reports out of Europe and Asia.This was not just a U.S. phenomenon.It seems the entire world has been disarmed of nuclear weapons.
五角大  已_J  之前l射的核         碜杂   以色列    中
The Pentagon has confirmed multiple launches...from Russia, as well as the UK, Israel and China.
- 看 天 上
- Look! - Look up there!
至今  白m    未l表  任何明
So far, there has been no response from the White House.
全球  多家  媒w  收到大量   目粝息
Eyewitness reports have been pouring in...from affiliates across the globe.
局   未_定    事件  背後的寓意       是和平  是  挑
Authorities are not sure...if it was an act of peace or an act of war.
尊敬的  上帝       指引我    走向光明
Our dear Father...hold me in the light of God.
死的  是我
It should have been me.
我弟  注定  成就  一番事I
He was the one that was gonna do something with his life.
他是  望所w
He was always the one.
可他不  @N想
That's not how he felt.
他X得  你才是     那人
He felt you were the one that was gonna do something special with your life.
你 影  世界
That you were gonna make a difference in the world.
甚至  改  世界
Maybe even change it.
你怎N  懂他
How do you know what he felt?
我能到   每人的  心
I know what everybody feels.
指引 我  走向光明       使我免受害
Hold me in the light of God.  Protect me from danger.
用你的力量保o我      聆我的祈\
Save me by Your command.  Listen to my prayer.
拯救你的子民
And keep me safe.
你限制了我的能力    怎Nk到的
You're blocking me. How?
我能  阻跄  侵入  他的意R
I can shield their minds from your power.
@是  我 不  m命   吸收的天x之一
It's one of the many gifts I've acquired throughout the millennia.
但是    我只能防守   s  不能M攻
But to see...inside a mind...
攻Me人的大X    @只有你
to control it...that's your gift.
你已  提前 看到了    Π      地球  即l生的盛典
You saw it, didn't you?The glory of what's to come.
你也要  ⑴c  屠 地球
You're going to take part in all this killing and...destruction?
我eox
It's all I've ever known.
不   你 有
No, it isn't.
你只是忘了
You've just forgotten.
不   查斯   我全得
No, Charles, I remember.
你的  方式   行不通
Your way doesn't work.
我o了他   一  更好的  方式
I've shown him a better way.
更好的  世界
A better world.
你就是    利用了 他的   怒 和  痛苦       唆使 他
No, you've just tapped into his rage and pain.That's all you've done.
咱 第一次 JRr    我就和你f^          在你心Y    我看到了  美好
I told you from the moment I met you, there is more to you,  There is good in you, too.
o你  r  看到了  什N
Whatever it is you think you saw in me, Charles...
美好的我   已 c我的家人   合葬了
I buried it...with my family.
怎N了
What?
他成  {子 了
What's wrong with you?
我  都  成  {子
Is that going to happen to all of us?
不  只有我      我把落在家Y了
No, I just...left my meds in the house.
l生什N了 @是哪
What happened? Where are we?
嗨
Hey!
你好 魔形女
Hello, Mystique.
史崔克  少校
Major Stryker.
我 x 上校 了
Colonel Stryker.
如果 我是你    我 x hc      因 不舒服
I wouldn't get too close to the wall,if I were you.It may create some discomfort.
我是  莫伊拉 ・ 格泰戈特
I'm Moira MacTaggert.
中央情缶    高特工
I'm a senior officer at the CIA.
我知道你是l    格泰戈特  特工
I know who you are, Agent MacTaggert.
你]嘞   把我P在@
You cannot keep me here, in this...
我 有嘞
Actually, I can.
一  控制意念的  N人       Я  倪@  到莫斯科的   所有核武器
A psychic event just   destroyed every nuke from here to Moscow.
而  r  在他  的家Y
That event emanated from exactly where we found you.
地球上  最的  意念 控制者
At the home of the world's most powerful psychic.
所以   告V我      查斯  在哪
So, you are going to tell me,where is Charles Xavier?
你 心的  不是  查斯        有一  比他  更大
It's not him you should be worried about.There's someone else.Someone more powerful.
如果你  放我出去    我湍阏
If you let us out of here,we can help you.
我敢信你
Do you really expect me to believe that?
你可以  窝b任何人       可我知道你是l ……
You can put on any face that you want,but I know who you are.
…… 你的 能耐
What you are.
嗨 莫伊拉
Hey, Moira.
你才f
What did you mean when you said...
有人  比查斯  更大  是什N意思
someone more powerful than Charles?
等一Y束    我就出l
Once they finish these,we'll go from there.
怎N  ]搞定
What's taking so long?
我M不去
I can't get in.
Y面  的磁  和 直升CY  一
They have a field around it,like the helicopter.
切   源
There's gotta be a way to cut the power.
查斯  臀液腿世界
Charles...you will send a message … to every living mind
f  @世界   成 U墟         @是  恩・沙巴・奴  θ祟的土P
You will tell them that this earth will be laid waste.That it is I, En Sabah Nur...who will wreak this upon them.
F 在 就 f
Now...deliver my message.
就算 我想f    但]有主X    我自己]那N大能量
Even if I wanted to...I couldn't reach that many people.I don't have Cerebro.
不需要  C器
You don't need a machine...
增 你
to amplify your powers.
因   有 我 在
You have me.
夥   一_那架wC出去
Guys, that could be our way out of here.
你JR  f磁王
You know him? Magneto?
以前 t解
I used to.
F在 不知道 了
Not so sure anymore.
他是  什N拥娜
What was he like?
他是不是
Was he...
像大家  f的那 ……
like they say he was? Was he...
人
the bad guy?
不
No.
我是f  是的
I mean, yeah.
年他
He was...
你P心  他的人品  质颤N
Why do you care so much? You see his speech on TV or something?
是 ……
Yeah, but...
他是   我H爹
He's my father.
啊 ？
What?
- 我 和 他 ……
- @我知道
- Him and my mom, they did it. - No, I know...
可 你_定
Are you sure?
然     我出生不久  他就   我
Yeah. Yeah.  He left my mom before I was born.
1 0  年前    我  退  逃z呢        可r  不知道  他是 我爹
I met him 10 years back...but I didn't know it was him.
我知道r    他已走了
By the time I figured it out,it was too late.
上Y拜  我 在上  看到了他
Then, this week I saw him on TV again...
所以  我才  大老h 跑  找他
and I came to that house,looking for him...
但我  到了以後
but by the time I got there...
他又 走了
Late again.
像我  @N快 的人
For a guy who moves as fast as me...
也有  聿患  的r候
I always seem to be too late.
希望  @次  不
Let's hope not this time.
是的   我也@N想的
Yeah. Seriously.
著
Hear me...
地球上  所有人
inhabitants of this world.
- 怎N回事
- @是  一  忠告
- What is that? - This is a message.
是 教 授
I think it's the Professor.
忠告你  每一人    有   N人
A message to every man, woman,and mutant in the world.
你  迷失了  方向
You have lost your way.
但是  我砹
But I have returned.
大判   即⒌
The day of reckoning is here.
你  建立的
All your buildings...
所有  F代化的  |西 ……
...all of your towers and temples...
都  崩
Will fall.
新的o元   即 _
And the dawn of a new age will rise.
於  未
...for there is nothing you can do...
- 你  ]有  x   【  琴 】
- ...to stop what is coming.- Jean.
【  琴  到我了    集中精力   跟著我的音   找到我  】
Jean, if you can hear me,focus on my voice.Cairo. Find us, Jean.
【  我大位置   在__   琴  】
Find us. Cairo. Find us.
@l消息    目的只有一
This message is for one reason alone.
告V   你之中  最的人
To tell the strongest among you...
碛  巨大力量  的人
Those with the greatest power...
在地球       放v  你的  j望
this earth will be yours.
碛  巨大力量  的人
Those with the greatest power...
保o    其他的人
protect those without.
@是  一  忠告
That's my message to the world.
]有主X    查斯  怎N做的
How was Charles doing that without Cerebro?
L官    才怎N回事
Sir, what was that voice?
我JR那音    是 删S     怎N回事
I know that voice. It's Xavier, isn't it? What's going on?
- 我也不知道
- 我不知道   哥
- We don't know! - We don't know, bro!
我到他了
He just spoke to me.
我也  到了
I think he spoke to everyone.
- 我也到了
- 不    有一l  [藏的  信息
- I could hear him, too. - No, no...he just sent me a hidden message.
他f  @一l   只有我  能到
One he knew only I would hear.
我知道他在哪
I know where they are.
嗨
Hey!
有    哪淼
We have shots fired! Where's it coming from?
他怎NM淼
How did they get in here?
六^ lF  入侵者
I have intruders in Quad Six.
派一人  去解Q
Send a security team. Take them out.
是lC   M去看看
The generator. It's worth a shot.
特
Kurt?
Y面好像有游
There's some kind of animal in there.
不是 游
It's no animal.
是人
It's a man.
他是l
Who is he?
他的  部分  被消除了
That part of him as been taken away.
什N意思
What do you mean?
他  把他
I mean they turned him into...
成了  武器
some kind of weapon.
第三M    回答   找到目肆]
Charlie Three, report. Did you find them?
把它P掉
Shut it down.
_火
Fire!
X武器  已逃逸
Weapon X is loose!
重}      X武器   已逃逸
I repeat, Weapon X is loose!
_J  @不是  游  ？
You sure he's not an animal?
他在中央大d
He's into the central halls.
第 5 ^    lF 目
Engaging target Sector  Five.
阻止不了他
We can't...
嘿
Hey!
- 他在致
-  出 什N事 了
- What are they doing? - What's going on?
【 ]子了 】
I Just lost feed.
我R上回
I'll be right back.
住手
No!
e   e^
Hey! Stay where you are!
斯科特 等等
Scott, wait.
我可以湍
I can help you.
琴
Jean.
_根
Logan.
你做了什N
What'd you do to him?
找回了  他一部分
I found a piece of his past and gave it back to him.
我 只能  找到  @些
Just the few memories I could reach.
希望 跟他   e再了
I hope that's the last we've seen of that guy.
特
Kurt.
- 什N
- What?
嗨
Hey.
xT hc      要炸T
Stay away from the...
什N
The what?
xT
The do...
xTh
Stay away from the...
xTh一c
Get away from the door!
我档饺
On three.
一 二
One... two...
我知道教授在哪毫
We know where the Professor is.
我有k法x_@
I think we might have a way out of here.
-  你挺害啊
- 有  ёψ拥娜   土宋
Well, you've been busy.We had a little help.
我走
Let's go!
小 心
Jesus!
噢   抱歉
Oh, sorry!
@
This way!
r  要不是   有人   背叛我
This was meant to be the center of the universe...
@Y  是   宇宙中心
before I was betrayed.
F在
Now...
我回砹
it will be.
酷
Nice.
h克    你 _@
Hey, Hank, do you think you can fly this thing?
我X得  有T
Yeah, I can figure it out.
伙
Hey, guys.
w 行 衣
Flight suits.
F在有了  痿YC
You got your warplane.
_  吧
Let's go to war.
@份Y物      碜  被你 下的  ^去          和你  需要的   未
A gift... from the past you left behind...and the future that lies ahead.
向地下   感受你的力量    孩子
You will reach down, my son.
深入 地心
Deep into the earth.
摧  人  建的一切
Rip everything they've built from the ground.
洗Q  地球
Wipe clean this world.
之後    我ьI  存者      建造 共a主x
And we will lead those that survive...into a better one.
那我呢
And me?
在@之中     我是  什N 角色
Am I to play a role in this madness?
最重要的  角色
You have the most important role of all.
你害怕
Were you scared?
年在A盛D  你害怕
That day in D.C., were you scared?
不
No.
但  《 第 一  》 r  我害怕
But I was scared on my first mission.
也是@拥娘wC    我和夥伴一起
I was on a plane like this with my friends.
我r  和你F在  差不多大
About your age.
我  叫自己   X 鹁
We called ourselves the X-Men.
r  你弟弟  也在wC上
Your brother was there.
我 叫他  n舨
We used to call him Havok.
那r  他的能力   也很y控制
He was a real handful...
可他  在痿Y中   非常勇敢
but when it came down to it,he was very brave.
那些孩子  後  怎N恿
What happened to the rest of the kids who went with you?
X 鹁
The X-Men?
只有我和h克活著
Hank and I are the only ones left.
我救不了其他人
I couldn't save the rest of them.
我f^   我不是英雄
I told you, I'm not a hero.
在我心中   你就是英雄
Well, you're a hero to us.
那天    在上 看到     影了我的一生
Seeing you that day on changed my life.
我也是
Mine, too.
m然  我住在  我家的  地下室
I still live in my mom's basement but, you know...
精神上好    可物|上 ……
everything else is...
我是  老幼
It's pretty much the same.
他  f我是  沤z
I'm a total loser.
@是  地球磁 ∽
What we're seeing is a magnetic phenomenon...
模    比 W斯S辛  那次更大
on a much larger scale than what we saw at Auschwitz.
地球  N藏著   各N  金僭素
The ground is full of magnetic elements.
F
Iron, nickel, cobalt.
海底  也是  如此
The ocean's floor is lined with them, too.
@次∽  已  地球 最深   _始了
It's already begun at the lowest depths.
大K   能阻跻魂   但挺不了 太久      最K  家   城市 ……
Land masses will slow it,but not for long.Eventually, cities, urban centers...
青~器r代  造的一切文明    都  消失      至少  要死  资|人
anything built since the Bronze Age...will be wiped away.The death toll will be in the billions.
@ T M  不就是  全地球
He's talking about the whole goddamn world.
你  不^是  一  紊裾婺
You're just another false god.
@一次Y束後  跟著你的人       t早    再 背叛你
And whoever's left to follow you when this all over...they will betray you again.
你e了   查斯
You're wrong, Charles.
浊Т蔚  中    只有@一次 ……
For the first time in a thousand lifetimes...
我遇了你
I have you.
我 碛  o  天x        只有一  我最需要 ……
For all my gifts,I have yet to possess the one I needed most.
自己 ……
To be...
…… o不在
everywhere.
控 制  ……  思想  ……  不再需要  愚 民    _      也一涌梢  制
To be...everyone.
十二c方向   吉_金字塔
Seventh wonder, twelve o'clock.
教授  在 金字塔 Y
has the Professor in the center of the pyramid.
他要把  自己的意R  D移到  教授身上
He's going to transfer his consciousness into the Professor.
如果他做到了
If he does that,
他能控制   每一人的  思想
he'll have the power to control every mind in the world.
那  到底  是什N
What the hell is that?
是  艾瑞克
It's Erik.
你   夜行者  到金字塔 Y
You guys help Nightcrawler get into the pyramid.
救出 查斯      我去Ω  艾瑞克
Get Charles. I'll take care of Erik.
我  怎N  ^去
How are we gonna get through that?
我你^去
I can get you in there.
我樗而   我一起去
I came here for him. Let me help you.
剩下的人   救出查斯   回到@   然後撤
The rest of you, get Charles on this plane and get him out of here.
- 那 怎Nk
- e心
- We're not leaving without you! - Don't worry.
我s上的
We'll catch up.
坐了
Hold on.
h克   你ьI孩子
Hank, you go with the kids.
- 莫伊拉   留在wC上
- 等等
- Moira will be waiting on the plane. - Wait.
怎N了
What?
我    控制不好  能力
Not all of us can fully control our powers.
e 控 制
Then don't.
完全  放_了 打
You need to embrace them.
我也一
We all do.
守住 @Y
Go. Join the others.
保我周全    直到  完成  D移
Protect me,until the transference is complete.
有  入口
There's an entrance. It's clear.
特   快M去
Kurt! Get in there!
M金字塔  兔     走
In the pyramid! Move!
快
Go!
把他 分_
Split them up.
教授
Professor...
特   快聿患傲
Kurt, you have to hurry!
我找不著   @ 像迷m
I'm trying. It's like a maze in here.
特  不
Kurt, no!
磁鎏   穿不^去
The magnetic field is too strong.I can't get us in there.
艾瑞克
Erik!
魔 形 女
Mystique.
你以      你 生o可   了
I know you think you've lost everything.
但你  有我
But you haven't.You have me.
有查斯
You have Charles.
你有  其他H人
You have more family than you know.
之前   你]救出  家人
You never had the chance to save your family before.
F 在 行
But you do now.
我就想   告V你   @
That's what I've come here to tell you.
那你呢
And you?
我是你的 ……
I'm your...
我也  家人
I'm here for my family, too.
L 出 去
Get out. Get out!
L出去
Get out!
再了
Auf Wiedersehen.
他 猿  不住了
We're losing him.
我很快  就回
I'll be right back.
斯科特   戴上眼R
Scott, glasses on!
我走
Let's go!
-  - 起w
- Locked on. - Here we go.
`蝶
Psylocke!
什N |西
What the hell was that?
特
Kurt.
所有人   抓o   夜行者
Everyone, grab hold of Nightcrawler!
- 我 Р   @N多人
- 把我щx@
-I've never done it with this many people.-Get us out of here.
特    快
Kurt, hurry!
特
Kurt!
查斯
Charles...
他]事吧
Is he okay?
- 他只是筋疲力M了
It's his energy. He's drained.
L出去
Get out.
Get out!
教授   ]事了  是我
Professor, it's okay. You're with us.
]事了
It's okay.
我要    去拚命了 ……
I'm going to fight for what I have left.
…… 你 呢
Are you?
我看到 你的心  不是只有  痛苦   怒      有甜美的回
There's so much more to you than you know.
你的  不只是我    有你的美好世界
It's not just me you're walking away from.
我需要你   艾瑞克
And it needs you, Erik.
一群   不中用的
Useless.
查斯
Charles.
我知道   你能到我
I know you can hear me.
我    ]完全   嗦
We're still connected.
查斯
Charles!
出  吧
Show yourself!
查斯
Charles!
出  吧
Show yourself!
o聊的  孩子
Foolish child.
彼得
Peter.
了Y他
End him.
【 我 的 偶 像 】
瑞雯
Raven.
ゴ蟮  英雄
The great hero.
- 我去救他
- 我和你一起去
I'm going out there.I'm going with you.
不
No.
他要的是我
It's me he wants.
查斯   你不能自投_W
Charles, you can't give yourself up.
他找到你     就能  控制  所有人     世界
If he has you, he has us all.The whole world.
你也  ]什N  本事       和你的 同伴 一
You are feeble. Just like the others.
查斯
Charles!
出
Come!
拯救   弱者
Rescue your weaklings!
奚 自己    拯救 大家
Give your life for theirs!
不
No.
他f得  ……
He was right.
我和他    ]完全   嗦
There is still some part of me connected to him.
查斯
Charles!
我能  u  他的 意R
I can get inside his head.
你  袖手旁^
Will you do nothing?
xx你  我入侵
Thank you for letting me in.
想要  我的能力 是吧
You want what I have?
想  感受 一下
You want to feel what I feel?
g迎淼轿业氖澜
Welcome to my world!
F在 在我的地P
You're in my house now!
你 吞得下我
You'll need a bigger house.
你 敢  背叛我
You betray me?
不
No.
我背叛的   是他
I betrayed them.
我  去 救 人
Let's jump.
什N
What?
掩o我
Cover me.
]事了
I got you.
使
Come on!
@些救兵    不大
They lack strength, Charles.
琴
Jean.
^
Come here.
……
Help...
…… 我
me.
待在@
Stay here.
他    醪蛔 他
They can't stop him.
琴
Jean.
臀
Help me!
h克
Hank!
Y束了   查斯   你完了
It's over, Charles. You're finished.
我 A 了
You're mine now.
你  永h  A不了
You will never win.
槭颤N呢
And why is that?
因    你是   孤家寡人
Because you are alone.
而我    不是
And I am not!
放 ……
Let...
…… 一 切
go.
放  你的  一切力量    琴
Unleash your power, Jean.
不 害 怕
No fear.
放    所有的    力量  ……
Unleash your power!
放 手 干       琴 ……
Let go, Jean!
…… 琴      放 手 干 ！
Jean, let go!
他想  遁形
He's getting away.
一切    早已  揭
All is revealed.
查斯 查斯
Charles! Charles!
- 我  失去他了
- 查斯
- We've lost him! - Charles.
- 他死了
- 不 查斯
- He's gone. - No, Charles.
查斯
Charles...
他 ] 死
No, he's not.
我能  感受到   他  的能量
I can still feel him.
xx   琴
Thank you, Jean.
查斯
Charles?
你知道  你在哪
Charles, do you know where you are?
我在海 ……
I'm on a beach.
…… 在古巴 ……
In Cuba.
…… 和你一起
With you.
什N海
What beach?
查斯 ・ 艾克斯S
Charles Xavier.
不 起 ……
I'm sorry.
我不  抹去    的回
I should never have taken those from you.
等等
Hold on!
我e^了什N
What did I miss?
@只能是  上帝的 恩
It seems only by the grace of God...
才使 我   免於 全球性  浩劫
that the ominous destruction seen from one end of the globe to the other, has stopped.
今早  情rf明上     中情局特工  莫伊拉    向{查M透露 ……
At a debriefing today,CIA Special Agent Moira MacTaggert...revealed to an investigative committee...
砺凡幻鞯  在逃犯  艾瑞克   竟然是  大功臣
The committee was further stunned to learn  aided in defeating this powerful and unknown...
上帝  到了  我的  祈\
I think our prayers were answered.
xx   y先生
Thank you, Mr. President.
每  公  接受了  N人      他  在的  巨大力量 ……
The potential destructive power of mutants... is sure to fuel new controversy and debate...
再次 造成     全球 恐慌
at a time when mutants were becoming accepted around the world.
魔形女f     他是 你爸
Mystique told me he is your father.
你告V他
Are you gonna tell him?
…  早晚的事
I might...one day.
F在  我只想  在@  待一段rg
I think for now, I'm just gonna stick around here for a while.
我 也 想
Me, too.
各  已在  重新  打造  自己的  火
The world's already begun rebuilding its arsenals.
凡人的  劣根性    查斯
It's human nature, Charles.
我仍然要    向  正面的  方向
I still have hope.
然
Oh, yes.
希 望
"Hope."
我  至少    瑞 雯  的判  是Φ
I was right about Raven.
我δ  的判   也]e
I was even right about you.
那   世界 其他人  的判嗄
What about the rest of the world?
你不怕  有一天  他  追 你和妻  你的W生           你做^  @拥
Doesn't it ever wake you up in the middle of the night?The feeling that one day they'll come for you...
我舻竭^
It does, indeed.
那你  醒磲  怎N做
What do you do when you wake up to that?
那些  W校  找麻┑娜
I feel a great swell of pity for the poor soul...
我只能f  z憾
that comes to my school looking for trouble.
你_定了  要走
You're sure I can't convince you to stay?
你可以  控制我的意念   查兄       你能f服我  槟阕鋈魏问
You're psychic, Charles.You can convince me to do anything.
再了   艾兄
Goodbye, old friend.
好\     教授
Good luck, Professor.
忘了  你所知道的  一切
Forget everything you think you know.
o  你在  W校  W了什N ……
Whatever lessons you learned in school...
父母 v的道理 ……
whatever your parents taught you.
那些  不m用於
None of that matters!
你  不是  孩子 ……
You're not kids anymore.
不是W生 ……
You're not students.
你是  X 鹗
You're X-Men.
司S溥（中文台~t生）  thank for watching